In this video, we're gonna talk about the main difficulty with Recursive Descent
在这段视频中，我们将讨论递归下降的主要困难
Parsing, a problem known as Left Recursion. Let's consider a very simple
解析，这是一个称为左递归的问题。让我们考虑一个非常简单的
grammar that consist of only one production, s goes to s followed by a. So
只包含一个结果的语法，s转到s，后面跟着a。所以
the Recursive Descent Algorithm for this production is the following. So, we just
此产品的递归下降算法如下所示。所以，我们只是
have a function called s1 for the first production of s. And it's going to succeed
我有一个名为s1的函数，用于s的第一次生成。它将会成功
if the function s succeeds and then after that succeeds we see a terminal a in the
如果函数s成功，则在成功之后，我们将在
input stream. And then we have to write a function for the symbol s itself and since
输入流。然后，我们必须为符号s本身编写一个函数，因为
there's only one alternative, there's only one production for s we don't need to
只有一种选择，只有一种我们不需要的产品
worry about backtracking or anything. So as we'll succeed exactly when as one
担心走回头路之类的。所以当我们合二为一的时候我们就会成功
succeed. There's only one possibility in this case and now I think you can see the
成功。在这种情况下只有一种可能性，现在我想你可以看到
problem what's going to happen. Well, when we go to parse an input string, we're
问题是会发生什么事。嗯，当我们要解析输入字符串时，我们
going to call the function s which is going to call the function s1. And then
将调用函数s，该函数将调用函数s1。然后
what the function as one gonna do well, the very first thing it's going to do is
作为一个人的功能要做好的，它要做的第一件事就是
to call the function s again. And as a result, the function s is going to go into
若要再次调用函数%s，请执行以下操作。因此，函数s将进入
an infinite loop and we're never going to succeed in parsing any input. This will
无限循环，我们永远不会成功解析任何输入。这将是
always go into an infinite loop. So, The reason that this, this grammar doesn't
总是进入无限循环。所以，这个，这个语法不是这样的原因
behave very well is because it is left recursive. And a left recursive grammar is
表现非常好是因为它是左递归的。左递归语法是
any grammar that has a non-terminal where if you start with that non-terminal and
任何具有非终止符的语法，如果您从该非终止符开始，并且
you do some non-empty sequence of re-writes. Notice the plus there. You have
您执行一些非空的重写序列。注意那里的加号。你有
to do more than one re-write. So, if you're actually doing a sequence of
进行不止一次重写。所以，如果你真的在做一系列
replacements, you get back to a situation where you have the same symbol still in
替换，您会回到一个情况，在此情况下，您仍然有相同的符号
the left most position. And you can see, this is not going to be good for parsing.
最左边的位置。您可以看到，这不利于解析。
So, in the case of this grammar up here, what happens while we get s goes to sa it
那么，在上面这个语法的例子中，当我们得到s的时候，会发生什么呢？
goes to saa goes to saaa. And so on and we can always get to a situation where we
去SAA去SAAA。以此类推，我们总能达到这样的境地
have a long string of a's and an s on the left end of the string. And if we always
在字符串的左端有一长串a和s。如果我们总是
have an s on the left end of the string, we can never manage any input because the
在字符串的左端有s，我们永远不能管理任何输入，因为
only way we manage input is if the first thing we generate is a terminal symbol.
我们管理输入的唯一方法是，如果我们生成的第一个东西是终端符号。
But if the first thing is always a non-terminal, we will never make any
但如果第一件事总是非终结符，我们将永远不会做任何
progress. And, it just doesn't work. I mean, Recursive Descent does not work with
进步了。而且，它就是不起作用。我是说，递归下降不适用于
Left-Recursive Grammars. Well, this seems like a major problem with recursive to
左递归文法。嗯，这似乎是递归到的一个主要问题
same parsing. It is a problem but as we'll see shortly it's really not so major. So
同样的解析。这是个问题，但正如我们很快会看到的，它真的不是那么严重。所以
let's consider a left-recursive grammar that slightly more general form. So here
让我们考虑一种稍微更一般形式的左递归语法。所以在这里
we have two productions now for s, s goes to s followed by something alpha or it
我们现在有两个关于s的乘积，s转到s，后面跟着某个alpha或它
goes to something else that doesn't mention s and let's call that Beta. And if
转到其他没有提到s的地方，我们称它为Beta。如果
you think about the language that this generates, it's gonna join all strings
你想一想这会产生的语言，它会把所有的字符串连接起来
that start with a beta and then follow, and followed by any number of alphas. And,
从测试版开始，然后是任意数量的阿尔法。和,
but it does it in a very particular way. So if I write out some, a derivation here
但它是以一种非常特殊的方式做到这一点的。所以如果我在这里写出一些，一个派生
where I used a few, where I used the first production a few times. You can see what's
在那里我使用了一些，在那里我使用了第一部作品几次。你可以看到是什么
going on. So again, s goes to s followed by alpha. And then s goes to s followed by
还在继续。所以再一次，s转到s，然后是alpha。然后s转到s，后跟s。
alpha, alpha and then s goes to s followed by alpha, alpha, alpha and if I repeat
阿尔法，阿尔法，然后是s，后跟阿尔法，如果我重复
this, I get. S followed by any number of alphas and then in one more step, I can.
这个，我明白了。s后面跟着任意数量的字母，然后再多走一步，我就可以了。
Put in beta and I get beta followed by any number of alpha. So, that's the proof that
输入Beta，我得到的是Beta，后面跟着任意数量的α。所以，这就是证明
it generates that language. That language that begins with a beta and has some
它产生了这种语言。该语言以测试版开始，并且有一些
sequence of alphas but you can see that it does it right to left, it produces the
序列，但是您可以看到它是从右到左操作的，它产生
right under the string first and in fact the very last thing it produces if the
首先在字符串下面，实际上也是它产生的最后一件事，如果
first thing that appears in the input and that's why. It doesn't work with Recursive
在输入中出现的第一件事，这就是原因。它不适用于递归
Descent Parsing because Recursive Descent Parsing wants to see the first part of the
下降解析，因为递归下降解析希望看到
input first and then work left to right. And this grammar is built to produce the
先输入，然后从左到右操作。而这个语法是用来生成
string right to left. And therein lies the idea that allow us to fix the problem so
字符串从右到左。其中蕴含着这样一种想法，那就是让我们能够这样解决这个问题
we can generate exactly the same language producing the strings from left to right
我们可以生成完全相同的语言，从左到右生成字符串
instead of right to left and th e way we do that is to replace left-recursion by
而不是从右到左，我们这样做是将左递归替换为
right-recursion. And this requires us to add one more symbol in this case to the
右递归。这需要我们在本例中再添加一个符号到
grammar so instead of having s go to something involving s on the left, we'll
语法，所以不用转到左边涉及s的部分，我们将
have s go to beta so the first thing notice in the very first position and then
必须转到测试版，所以首先要注意的是第一个位置，然后
it goes to s prime and what does s prime do, well s prime produce what you would
它转到s素数，而s素数的作用是什么，好吧，s素数产生你想要的结果。
expect, a sequence of alphas and it could be the empty sequence. And if you write
期望是一个字母序列，它可能是空序列。如果你写下
out some you know? Example derivation here we'll have s goes to beta s prime. Which
你知道吗？示例推导，这里我们有s到βs素数。哪一个
goes to now using the rules for s prime goes to beta alpha s prime, Goes to beta
到现在为止，使用s素数的规则，得到βαs素数，再到βαs素数。
alpha. Alpha s prime goes to and after any number of sequent, any number of rewrites
阿尔法。Alpha的质数在任意数量的顺序、任意数量的重写之后进行。
we get beta followed by sub sequence of alphas followed by s prime. And then in
我们得到β，然后是α子序列，然后是s素数。然后在
one more step we use the Epsilon Rule here and we wind up with beta followed by some
再往下一步，我们在这里使用Epsilon规则，最终得到测试版，然后是
number of alphas. And so you can see it generates exactly the same string as the
阿尔法的数量。所以您可以看到它生成的字符串与
first grammar but it does so in a right-recursive way instead of a
第一个语法，但它是以右递归方式实现的，而不是
left-recursive way. So in general, we may have many productions some of which are
左递归法。所以一般说来，我们可能有很多作品，其中一些是
left-recursive and some of which are not. And the language produced by this
左递归的，有些不是左递归的。以及由此产生的语言
particular form of grammar here is gonna be all the strings. They are derived from
这里的特殊语法形式是所有的字符串。它们派生自
asst start with one of the betas. So one of the things here that doesn't involve s
先从其中一个测试版开始。所以这里有一件事没有涉及到
and it continues with zero or more instances of the alphas. And we can do
并且它以零个或多个阿尔法实例继续。我们能做的就是
exactly the same trick. This is just generalizing the idea that we had before
完全一样的把戏。这只是我们以前的想法的推广
where we only have one beta and one alpha to many betas and many alphas and so the
我们只有一个贝塔和一个阿尔法到很多贝塔和阿尔法，所以
general form of rewriting this left-recursive grammar in using
改写这种左递归语法的一般形式
right-recursion is given here. So here each of the betas appears as an
这里给出了右递归。因此，这里的每个测试版都显示为
alternative in the first position. We only need one additional symbol s prime and
第一个位置的备选方案。我们只需要一个额外的符号s素数和
then the s prime rules is take care of generating any sequence of the alpha i.
则s个质数规则负责生成αi的任何序列。
Now it turns out that, that isn't the most general form of left recursion. There are
现在事实证明，这不是最一般的左递归形式。确实有
even other ways to encode left recursion in a grammar and here's another way that's
甚至是在语法中编码左递归的其他方法，这里还有另一种方法，即
important. So, we may have a grammar that where nothing is obviously left-recursive.
很重要。所以，我们可能有一个语法，其中没有任何东西明显是左递归的。
So if you look here, you see that the s doesn't even appear on the right hand side
所以如果你看这里，你会发现s甚至没有出现在右手边
here. And if you look at this production here, a doesn't appear anywhere on the
这里。如果你看这部作品，a没有出现在
right hand side so there's no what's called Immediate Left-Recursion in this
右手边，所以这里没有所谓的直接左递归
grammar. But on the other hand, there is left-recursion because s goes to a alpha
语法。但是另一方面，有左递归，因为s是α
and then a can go to s beta. And so there we have in, in two steps produce another
然后A可以转到Sβ。所以我们在这里，在两个步骤中产生另一个
string with s at the left end and so this is still a Left-Recursive Grammar. We just
左端有s的字符串，所以这仍然是一个左递归语法。我们只是
delayed it by inserting other non-terminals at the left most position
通过在最左侧位置插入其他非终端来延迟它
before we got back to s. So, this left recursion can also be eliminated. In fact,
在我们回到s之前，所以这个左递归也可以消除。事实上,
this can be eliminated automatically, it doesn't even require human intervention.
这可以自动消除，甚至不需要人工干预。
And if you look at any of the text pretty quickly in the Dragon Book, you'll find
如果你快速阅读“龙书”中的任何一篇文章，你会发现
algorithms were doing that.
算法就是这么做的。